Dima Hordiienko

Front End Developer (React.js)

Email: dima.hordiienko.ca@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitry-gordienko

Github: https://github.com/Odinokun
Website portfolio: https://odinokun.com

Phone: (613) 880-3813

Location: Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

Summary

I have worked as a front-end developer for 9 years, since 2014.

I have expertise:

- of professional front end, web or mobile software development using JavaScript, HTML and CSS;
- of coding the websites and web applications layout based on the provided design mockup;
- of developing with libraries React.js, Next.js, Vue.js;
- of developing with animation libraries like GSAP and Three, js;

I'm an adaptable, innovative, reliable and responsible developer. Also I'm a self-learner, problem solver and am not inclined to frequently change jobs.

Main skills

React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, Css3, Pug, Scss, Material UI, Tailwind, Jquery, Bootstrap, Webpack, Git, Google API.

Experience

Front End Developer

Aug 2022 - Nov 2023

Metame (remote)

Description: A platform that specializes in the creation and sale of NFT tokens, unique digital assets based on the blockchain (https://www.metamenft.io)

My responsibilities:

- handled the design, layouts and wire-frames of the user interface;
- launched project in production;
- contributed to the overall project design;
- developed and created new React components that enhance functionality and enable user interaction;
- used tools like GSAP to craft captivating and smooth animations that breathe life into the project's interface:
- worked with various APIs and engaged with backend systems to ensure the proper functioning and logic of the project;

Technologies: React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, Css3, React Hook Form, React-Query, React-Router, Headless UI, Redux-Toolkit, Material UI, Storybook, Tailwind, GSAP, Scss, Three.js, Webpack, Git, GitHub, Yarn, API, Svg

Front End Developer

Dec 2020 - July 2022

EpicentrK (Kyiv, Ukraine)

Description: The biggest trade platform in Ukraine (like Canadian Tire): building materials, FMCG, and others. They own a network of big supermarkets and a big online store (https://epicentrk.ua)

My responsibilities:

 created new pages and sections in the online store, ensuring convenient navigation and expanding functionality to enhance the user experience;

- optimized the existing portion of the store, conducting performance analysis, optimizing code, and improving page loading for increased speed and meeting user demands;
- developed separate landing pages for one-time and seasonal promotions, as well as sales, to attract customer attention, increase conversion rates, and boost sales;
- expanded internal tools such as CRM and admin panel, improving their functionality, adding new features, and facilitating efficient data management and analysis for the store team;

Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue.js, HTML5, Css3, Axios, Pug, Jade, Scss, Jquery, Jquery UI, Bootstrap, FancyBox, Slick.js, Swiper, Php, Nuxt.js, Vuex, Webpack, Git, Npm, API, Leaflet, OpenGraph, Svg.

Front End Developer

Apr 2017 - Nov 2020

Krasnyk Studio (Lviv, Ukraine)

Description: A dynamic web design studio, crafting user-centric websites. Innovative, responsive designs tailored to elevate diverse digital experiences. (https://krasnykstudio.com.ua)

My responsibilities:

- created layouts and wire-frames of the user interface;
- completed and launched 50+ projects of varying difficulty levels;
- increased studio profits by 10-15%;

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, Css3, Barba.js, Axios, GSAP, Pug/Jade, Sass/Scss/Less, Jquery, Jquery UI, Bootstrap, FancyBox, Slick.js, Swiper, Three.js, Git, GitHub, Npm, API, Google API, Leaflet, OpenGraph, Svg

Front End Developer

Oct 2014 - Apr 2017

MostOfDesign Studio (Kyiv, Ukraine)

Description: Creative web design studio crafting captivating, user-centric websites. Innovative, responsive designs tailored to elevate digital experiences across diverse industries.

(https://facebook.com/mostofdesign)

My responsibilities:

- managed the development team;
- created layouts and wire-frames of the user interface;
- implemented and launched 70+ projects of varying difficulty levels;
- increased studio profits by 10%;

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, Css3, Barba.js, Axios, GSAP, Pug, Sass/Scss/Less, Jquery, Jquery UI, Bootstrap, FancyBox, Slick.js, Swiper, Three.js, Git, GitHub, Npm, API, Google API, Leaflet, OpenGraph, Svg

Education

Bachelor's degree - Kyiv University of Tourism, Economics and Law (Ukraine, 2012)

Additional courses

React Developer Course (IT Incubator School) Complete JavaScript Course (Loftschool) Web Development for Advanced (Loftschool)

Skills

React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, Css3, Pug, Jade, Sass, Scss, Less, React-Bootstrap, React Hook Form, React-Query, React-Router, DaisyUI, Headless UI, Redux, Redux-Saga, Redux-Thunk, Redux-Toolkit, Material UI, MUI, Storybook, Tailwind, HTML, Css, Barba.js, Axios, GSAP, Chakra UI, Jquery, Jquery UI, Bootstrap, FancyBox, Slick.js, Swiper, Three.js, Vue.js, Ant Design, Php, Nuxt.js, Vuex, Webpack, Git, GitHub, Gulp, Grunt, Bower, Pnpm, Yarn, Npm, API, Google API, Leaflet, OpenGraph, Svg